(忆往昔)
有什么变了  很大
Something's changed. It's big.
跟上帝一样大  跟路西法一样大
Big as God. Big as Lucifer.
总得有人做点什么
Someone's gotta do something.
谁
Someone?
阿玛拉  你长大就会成为我
Amara, I am what you are becoming.
上帝把我关起来
God locked me away.
都是为满足他自己的自大
All for his own ego.
你得专注于我们的目标
You must stay fixed on our purpose.
-什么目的  -算笔旧账
- What's that? - Settle an old score.
你好  迪恩
Hello, Dean.
我的姑娘长大了
My girl's grown up.
我会饶你一命  但有个条件
I'll spare your life on one condition --
放迪恩安全离开
Safe passage for Dean out of here.
成交
Yes.
-阿玛拉消失了  -她是怎么逃走的
- Amara is in the wind. - How'd she get away?
"上帝的妹妹"这句话你没听明白吗
What part of "God's frickin' sister" did you not understand?
我们永远都会帮助彼此
We will always help each other.
上帝没分享过他的想法吧
I don't suppose God's decided to share any wisdom on the matter.
地狱里有个笼子
There's this cage in hell,
路西法被关在里面
and it's where they keep Lucifer.
我也曾被关在里面
And I've been in it,
上帝好像想让我回到那里
and I think God wants me to go back.
不可能的  我们会找到其他办法
Not happening. We'll find another way.
其他办法是什么
What is the other way?
(如今)
忏悔罪孽吧
Repent your sins!
是啊
Yes!
请求上帝宽恕吧
Beg for his divine mercy.
是啊
That's right!
等末日到来
When the end comes...
拯救我们吧  主
Save us, lord!
那一日必将到来
And come it will,
只有被宽恕者能升入天堂
only the forgiven will ascend to holy grace.
他在看着  他在等着
He's watching. He's waiting!
你是在说上帝吗
This is God you're speaking of?
你真觉得他在看吗
Do you really think he's watching?
他在对我们进行评判
Deciding which of us is worthy.
只有获选之人能升入天堂
Only the chosen will be raised to heaven.
那就是你吗
Oh, and that's...you?
老实说  我觉得他根本不在乎
Truthfully, I don't think he's all that interested.
他似乎都没怎么出现
He doesn't even seem to be around.
相信我  我找过的
Believe me, I've searched.
够了  姐妹
Stop right there, sister.
快祈求他的宽恕吧  否则就等着他降下盛怒
Beg for his forgiveness or face his terrible wrath.
-是啊  -是吗  他会生气吗
- That's right! - Really? Gets annoyed, does he?
他的盛怒有多种形式
His wrath comes in many forms.
但只有上帝能制造
But only God is able to create
-可怕的瘟疫和毁灭  -没错
- the fearsome plague and destruction... - That's right.
地球上的凡人必须皆向其屈服
that all on earth must bow before.
-正义在等着呢  -你是指这种吗
- Justice is waiting! - You mean something like this?
(忏悔吧  罪人)
那是你干的吗
Is it...you?
(天堂国度近在咫尺)
你在试炼我们吗
Are you testing us?
上帝吗  不是
God, you mean? No.
但这么说吧
But let's just say
他不是这儿的唯一玩家
he's not the only game in town.
不
Oh, no!
(末日将近)
亲爱的  想的美
Oh, honey, you wish.
出来啊
Well?
[邪恶力量 第11季第9集]
这真的是答案吗  这真是你想要的吗
Is this really the answer? Is this what you want?
因为这太疯狂了  而且绝不可能
Because it's crazy, okay? And it's not gonna happen.
我要说多少次  这是个坏主意
How many times do I have to say that this is a horrible idea?
那我要说多少次
About as many times as I have to say,
"好吧  那还有什么办法"
"Okay, then what else we got?"
听着  我愿听你出主意
Listen, I'm all ears.
迪恩  我一般会同意你的看法
Dean, ordinarily, I'd agree with you.
但只有我向上帝求助时才会看到这些幻象
But the visions only happen when I reach out to God.
我问他如何打败黑暗
I asked him for a way to beat the Darkness,
而幻象也变得更加具体
and the visions got more specific.
我在笼子里
And...I was in the cage.
嗯  跟路西法在一起
Yeah, with Lucifer,
史上最可怕的怪物
the biggest monster ever hatched.
-简直太棒了  -知道吗
- Fan-freakin'-tastic. - You know what?
路西法本来是史上最可怕的怪物
Lucifer was the biggest monster ever hatched,
直到你跟我放出了更可怕的怪物
until you and I hatched one that's even worse.
听着  在幻象里
Listen, in the vision,
路西法
Lucifer...
摸了我
touches me.
我觉得很平静
And I feel...calm,
(宗教集会遭遇闪电  8人被劈死)
感觉就像  不会有事的
like things will be all right.
而这种事我自己是想不到的
And that's not something I would ever come up with.
我绝不会那么想的
I mean, that is the last thing I would ever think.
如果路西法碰你了
If Lucifer touched you,
你就不会再有任何想法了
it would be the last thing you think, ever.
上帝为什么会要你这么做
Why would God even ask this of you?
而且  我们怎么能证明
And you know what? What proof do we have
这一切是真的
that any of this is actually real?
有个灌木丛着火了
There was a burning bush.
灌木丛着火
A burning bush?
就像《圣经》里那样
Like in the bible.
你当时在树林里
You were in the forest.
那里有灌木丛  有时候他们自己就会着火
There are bushes there and sometimes they burn.
知道吗
You know what, man?
或许这里面的确有什么
Maybe there is something to it all. Maybe.
也或许没有
And maybe there's not.
迪恩  这说得通啊
Dean, doesn't it make sense?
路西法肯定知道上帝是如何终结黑暗的
I mean, Lucifer would know how God ended the Darkness.
他当时也在
He was there.
上帝向你保证了吗
So God assured you of this, did he?
或许是你编的呢
Let's say you're making this up.
我倒从未觉得你这人有什么想象力
I mean, I never think of you as imaginative.
我们没说真会这么做
We're not saying it's gonna happen.
我们只想知道  理论上来讲
We just wanna know... theoretically,
这是否有可能
...if it's possible.
笼子是不该打开的
The cage is a can of worms you do not want to open.
-我们的谈话结束了  -是吗
- I believe this conversation is over. - Is it?
克劳力  你知道黑暗
Crowley, you know that the Darkness is gonna
不会放过任何事物  包括你
pound on everything, and that includes you.
是啊  本来她之前在你手里时
Yeah, and you had a shot at taking her out
你有机会除掉她
when she was with you,
但显然你以为讨好她会更合适
but apparently, you thought that sucking up was the way to go.
可结果却不怎么样
And that didn't work out so well.
因为她选了你
Because she chose you.
而你控制不好自己的女朋友
And you couldn't control your girlfriend.
当时在房间里发生了什么
What happened in that room?
她为什么非要饶你一命
Why did she insist on sparing you?
她对你来说算什么
What is she to you?
你想知道她是什么吗  克劳力
You wanna know what she is, Crowley?
上帝的妹妹怎么样
How about God's sister?
上帝的妹妹  他还有亲戚
God's sister? He has relatives?
我本来有那么好的筹码
I had that kind of leverage under my thumb
居然被我放走了
and I let it slip away.
我们能不能专注于大局
Can we focus on the big picture here, okay?
萨姆能不能跟路西法见个面
Can Sam meet with Lucifer or not?
-在笼子里  -不  不能在笼子里
- In the cage. - No, not in the cage.
那是不可能的
That's not gonna happen.
好吧  那我就见不到他了
Okay, then I don't meet with Lucifer.
迪恩  我们不能放他出来啊
Dean, we can't let him out.
怎么了
What?
或许有个办法
There may be a way.
不用说  如果萨姆进笼子  就出不来了
Clearly, if Sam enters the cage, he's gone.
是的  这的确在我的遗愿清单上
I mean, yes, it's on my bucket list,
但现在不是自私的时候
but now's not the time to be selfish.
需要一个安全的地点
Need a secure site,
想办法遏制路西法的法力
a way to neutralize Lucifer's powers.
在地狱吗
In hell?
是的  在地狱
Yes, in hell.
这样我们多少还能控制着点局面
So we have a modicum of control.
你以为我希望那怪物跑来楼上捣乱吗
You think I want that abomination running amok upstairs?
是否可以控制局面
Is it possible to control the situation?
如果不能保证萨姆安全  就休想了
Because if Sam's not safe, it's not happening.
老天啊  妈妈  别管那么严
Goodness mummy, loosen the grip.
理论上  有可能  有些困难
Theoretically, it's possible. There are challenges.
我可以安排你们下地狱
I can arrange a transit into hell.
但开笼子就是另一码事了
Opening the cage, that's another matter.
你是地狱之王啊  你没钥匙吗
You're the king of the joint. Don't you have a key?
那是上帝本人封印的  我当然"没钥匙"了
It was sealed by God himself. Of course I don't "have a key."
机关是上帝制造的
The mechanism is of divine manufacture.
我认为它的奥秘
I believe its secrets,
以及能保护萨姆的咒语
along with the spells for warding Sam,
与其他类似秘密都被记录在了一个地方
are recorded where many such mysteries are found.
《诅咒之书》
The Book of the Damned.
-太棒了  -谢谢
- Oh, that's wonderful. - Thank you.
很高兴再次见到你
Good to see you again, yes.
你好  玛丽  你好吗
Oh, hello, Mary. How are you?
-好多了  谢谢  -很好
- Oh, better. Thank you. - Good. Good.
艾格尼丝  见到你很高兴
Agnes, always a pleasure. Good to see you.
你好
Hello.
你是负责人吗  我在找上帝
Are you in charge here? I'm looking for God.
当然
Oh, of course.
我们都在万事万物里寻找上帝
We all look for God in all things.
不  我是需要找间屋子跟他见面
No, I need an actual meeting, in a room.
这就是最合适的地方
Well, it's the right place.
这是他的房子
This is his house.
想找到他  就得通过祈祷
And the way to reach him is through prayer.
像他们那样吗
Like them, you mean?
来吧  试试看
Go ahead. Take her out for a spin.
不好使
It's not working.
当然好使的  他能听到你
Oh, of course it's working. He heard you.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为他承诺了
Because he promised.
那么你见过他
Oh, so you have seen him then?
没人见过他
Well, no one has.
至少在世的没人见过
A-at least, no one alive.
等等  只有死人能看到他吗
Wait. So only dead people get to see him?
你们几十亿人觉得这没问题吗
And this makes sense to billions of you?
信仰就是如此
It is the nature of faith.
都在这里
It's... it's all here.
上帝的仁慈
The mercy of god,
他对世界和人类的爱
his love of the world and mankind,
他为我们准备的完美计划
his... his perfect plan for us.
这是操纵
Manipulation.
你只是相信他希望你相信的事
You only believe what he wants you to believe.
-是啊  -你根本不知道他什么样
- Exactly. - You don't know what he is like at all.
我们当然知道
We certainly do.
上帝是光
God is the light.
正是光战胜了黑暗
And it is the light that vanquishes the Darkness.
母亲  多谢你前来
Mother. Good of you to stop by.
放开我  白痴
Unhand me, you...goons.
费格斯  你以为你赢了吗
So, Fergus, think you've won?
你敢碰我
Lay a hand on me,
我的追随者就会用《诅咒之书》的力量
and my followers will swoop down on this tin can palace of yours
围攻你这座锡罐王宫
with all the power of The Book of the Damned.
闭嘴吧  你个满口谎言的贱人
Stow it, you lying bitch.
如果你能做到  你早做了
If you could do that, you'd have done it.
如果我想杀你  我也早做了
If I wanted to kill you, I'd have done that.
你可不是没试过
Not that you haven't tried.
你两次企图杀我
You tried to kill me twice.
怎么说的来着  第三次保准成功
What is it they say? Third time's the charm.
你不是要把我交给他们俩吧
Oh, you're not handing me over to them?
你都不该这么下作
It's beneath even you.
他们也是你的敌人
They're your enemies as well.
好了  罗威娜  没错  我们都是敌人
All right, Rowena, we get it. We're all enemies. Okay?
但现在  我们有更要紧的事
But right now, we got bigger fish to fry.
之后我们可以再继续互相残杀
Then we can go back to killing each other.
善恶终有报啊
The chicken's come home to roost.
血印被祛除时  有可怕的力量被释放了
This ghastly force set free when the mark was removed.
你知道
So you know.
我听过传言
I've heard whispers.
真如他们说的那么糟吗
As bad as they say?
这么说吧  这个房间里每个人
Well, let's just say that everyone in this room
或许都有把它关回去的一部分办法
might hold a piece of the puzzle to corking it back up.
是嘛
Oh, really?
那等危险过去之后  我又会如何呢
And what happens to me once the danger's past?
我怎么知道我能信任你们
How do I know I can trust any of you?
你不知道
You don't.
我们都不知道  这是魔鬼的交易
None of us do. It's a devil's bargain.
现在  所有天使必须团结
This is a time for all angels to pull together,
放下我们的争执
to put aside our disagreements,
让那些老大们看看  如何挽救天堂
and show the big bosses how to save heaven
不被夺去
from being taken over.
因为正是我们这些小兵会被踢到一边
'cause it's grunts like us who'll get kicked aside.
相信我
Believe me.
黑暗对上帝所有的创造物都有打算
The Darkness has a plan for every one of God's creations.
夺取天堂  这怎么可能
Take over heaven? How is that even possible?
是啊  是谁让她当上帝了
Yeah, who made her god?
拜托  丹尼尔
Come on, Daniel.
你跟我一样熟知那些传说
You know the stories as well as I do.
她法力高强  吞没一切
All powerful, all consuming.
她的仇是跟上帝  不是我们
Her beef is with god, not us.
他把她关了起来  该由他来摆平此事
He locked her away. It's on him to make this right.
是啊
Yeah.
那你下次见到他
And you tell him that
自己去跟他说这话吧
next time you see him.
他根本不在啊
He's not around.
是啊  他把她关了起来
Yeah. He locked her up.
你们觉得她不会想毁掉他所创造的一切
And you don't think she's gonna wanna get even
来向他报复吗
by tearing apart anything he ever made?
你要带领我们抵抗她吗
And you're gonna lead us against her?
你从未领导过任何人
You've never led anyone.
我们都没有
None of us have.
这怎么就不好了  毕竟我们的领袖成天
How is that a bad thing, when our leaders do nothing
就知道挑拨各派系之间的矛盾
but pit the factions against each other?
这事得靠我们
This is in our laps, guys.
把话传出去
So spread the word.
我们要放下争执
We get past our differences.
我们要联合起来
We stand united.
我们要采取行动
And we move.
马上行动
Now!
这能是真的吗
Can this be true?
他妹妹
His sister?
我们那年代  哪怕这么想
Oh, in my day, we'd all be burnt at the stake
都会被捆在柱子上烧死
for even thinking any of this.
所以  母亲  你看得出事情多么紧急
You see then, mother, the need for urgency.
如果我破译这本书这么要紧
Well, if my deciphering of the book is so pivotal,
我要知道我有什么好处
I'd like to know what's in it for me.
除了饶你一命吗
You mean, other than your life?
说起来
Speaking of which,
我跟你做个交易吧  妈妈
I'll make you a little deal, mummy.
你乖乖地帮忙
You pitch in, like a good girl,
我就叫我的刺客收手
I'll call off my assassins.
你暂时再不用提心吊胆了
No more looking over your shoulder...for now.
我需要法典  这不用说
I'll need the codex, of course.
还有查理编程的译码器
And the code breaker Charlie devised.
你能受限查阅  在监督之下
Yeah, you'll get limited access. Supervised.
我们要知道  如何打开笼子
We need to know exactly this... how to open the cage
等笼子打开后  如何保护萨姆
and how to protect Sam once it is.
这笼子里究竟有什么那么危险的东西
Just what's in this cage that's so dangerous?
路西法
Lucifer.
最初的黑暗王子吗
The original dark prince?
是的  坏蛋大天使
Yes, an archangel so badass
被上帝亲自丢进了笼子里
that he was personally dumped into the cage by God himself.
那我们赶紧开始吧
Let's get to it then, lads.
你能看到吗
Do you see what's happening?
你这些宠儿
All your favorites,
你的天选之民
all your chosen,
他们在受苦
they are suffering!
现身吧
Show yourself!
萨姆
Hey, Sammy.
抱歉让你负责看着女巫
Sorry to stick you with witch duty,
虽然听上去很有趣
as fun as that sounds.
非常有趣
Every bit.
但我们要找的东西绝对在书里
But the stuff we're looking for is definitely in the book.
别乱翻
No snooping around there.
集中注意力
Focus.
你在教堂有发现吗
You find anything at the church?
刚到  警察说
Uh, just got here. The cops said that the, uh,
最后看到活着的这些被害人时
the last time the vics were seen alive,
其中一位  一个牧师
one of them a priest,
在跟一个神秘的女人说话
they were talking to some mystery woman.
她没有遇害
She was not killed.
-是阿玛拉吗  -一定是
- Amara? - Yeah, I'm bettin'.
里面就是屠杀现场  到处是血
Apparently, it's a massacre. The place is covered in blood.
她的行为升级了
She's upping her game.
她早晚会让我们招架不住的
She's gonna pass the point where we can deal with her.
听好  你确定你
Listen, are you sure that you're...
真的愿意这么做吗
you're okay with this whole deal?
不  一点也不愿意
No. Not even a little.
但我们还有什么选择呢
But what choice do we have, you know?
好吧  那我要说  我讨厌这样
Okay, well, for the record, I hate it.
等着我  我到之前别干傻事
Just wait for me. Don't do anything until I get there.
现在只是在研究  但  好的
Right now it's just research, but you got it.
等你回来的
Nothing without you.
好
All right.
你还谈信任
You talk about trust.
我没有
No, I don't.
你和你嗜血的哥哥说我们是
You and your bloodthirsty brother say we're partners
对付阿玛拉的圣战搭档
in this holy war against Amara,
但是
and yet...
就这么信任我吗
trussed like a chicken.
你拿着《诅咒之书》坐在那儿
You're sitting there with The Book of the Damned
而且有破解咒语的一切手段
and the means to read every word,
你以为我会放你自由吗
and you think I'm gonna set you free?
你觉得我疯了吗
Do I look crazy?
你对你霸道的哥哥
Well, you do have unresolved issues
和父亲的抛弃
with your domineering older brother
还有未解开的心结啊
and the abandonment by your father.
赶紧继续工作吧
You know what? Just get back to work, all right?
我们要没时间了
We're running out of time here.
又怎么了
What? What now?
我需要些原料
Well, I'll need some ingredients,
但你可以把费格斯叫来了
but you may summon Fergus.
叫他推个手推车来
And tell him to bring a handcart.
手推车
A handcart?
我们要下地狱
We are going to hell.
热狗
Hot dog?
嗯  来一个
Yeah. Uh, one.
(萨姆来电)
萨姆  一切就绪  费格斯要来了
Sam, everything is in order. Fergus is coming.
我向迪恩保证过会打给他的
I promised Dean I'd call.
我还向林肯保证过晚上观剧会很愉快呢
I promised Lincoln a fun night at the theater.
事情总会变  必须马上行动了
Things change. It's now or never.
你感到了我的存在
You felt my presence.
所以才来到了这儿
That's why you came here.
你长大了
You grew up.
是啊
Yes.
你现在是这样了吗
So this is you now?
至少今天是的
At least for today.
担心吗  对即将发生的事感到害怕吗
Flop sweat, sonny? Dread of what's to come?
闭嘴
Can it.
你的俏皮话或许在女巫圈里吃得开
Your barbs may amuse your circle of hags,
但你根本不知道你要面对的是什么
but you have no idea what you're tampering with,
不知道路西法的本事
what Lucifer is capable of.
亲爱的  你如果承受不了
Well, dear, if you can't stand the heat,
就离开地狱啊
get out of hell.
我得说  风景不如我想的那么好
I must say, it's not as scenic as I'd expected.
我们在地狱最深处  边缘地带
We're in the furthest reaches of hell... limbo...
我只把最不守规矩的灵魂送来这儿
where I send unruly souls for time-outs.
我要在这儿见路西法吗
This is where I meet with Lucifer?
虽然气氛不佳  但绝对安全
What it lacks in ambience, it makes up for in security.
真让人皮肤发麻  是吧  小鹿
Makes your flesh crawl, doesn't it, moose?
我明白
I get it.
我是这里的国王
I'm the king of this place.
还是不喜欢这里
Still not my cup of tea.
我不知道  克劳力  我倒觉得这里适合你
I don't know, Crowley. I'd say it suits you.
黑暗
Dark.
空虚
Empty.
真棒  还这么鄙视我
Fascinating, the utter contempt,
我正要救你们温家人的命呢
when I'm in the midst of saving the Winchesters' bacon.
而且是又一次
Again.
这是为了救每一个人
The point of this is to save everyone's bacon,
包括你自己
including yours.
希望她是真的心里有数
Let's just hope she knows what she's doing.
如果防护咒不对  牢房什么都困不住
The cell won't hold crap if the warding's not right.
你别担心我  萨穆埃尔
Don't you worry about me, Samuel.
我可是专业人士
I'm a professional.
你确定你真可以做到
You're certain you can do this
不用真正打开笼子吗
without actually opening the cage?
我们就要知道了
We're about to find out, aren't we?
[咒语]
试试笼子吧
Now...let's have a go at that cage.
[咒语]
开始了
It begins.
你误解了我想在地球上做的事
You misunderstand my purpose on earth.
我误解了
Well, do I misunderstand
你在公园屠杀的人吗
the people you butchered in that park?
还有教堂的那些
Or in that church?
我总得想办法引起他的注意
I had to get his attention.
-他  -上帝
- "His"? - God.
我试过祈祷
I tried praying,
向他求助
calling out in need.
他无视了我
He ignored me.
是他迫我的
He forced my hand.
否则我没理由伤害他的天选之民
I had no other reason to harm his chosen.
我只跟我哥哥有仇
My issue is with my brother,
而不是他的创造物
not his creation.
无论你们两个之间是怎么回事
Whatever the deal is between you two,
是谁先动的手  谁是老爹的最爱
whoever threw the first punch, whoever was daddy's favorite...
我们没有老爹
There was no daddy.
随便吧
Whatever.
那是你的事
That mess is your mess.
你们俩之间的纠葛
It's between you two.
可你在夺取他人性命  他们的灵魂
You're taking people's lives. You're taking their souls.
我是吞噬了他们的灵魂
I consumed their souls.
他们并没有消失
They aren't gone.
而是成为了我的一部分
They're a part of me.
这样他们可以获得永生
And in that way, they live forever.
我的老朋友克劳力
My old friend Crowley.
我只不过是小助手  继承你的衣钵
A mere acolyte, carrying your torch.
你真好啊
You're too kind.
对你自己好
To yourself.
你想要我做什么
What do you want of me?
萨姆·温彻斯特
Sam Winchester.
我的老室友
My old roomie.
抱一个呗
Hug it out?
我得说  这见面让我有点懵
I gotta say, I'm a little in the dark about this meeting.
是要让我假释吗
Am I up for parole?
因不良表现而获得休假
Time off for bad behavior?
一般没人来探监的
I don't really get visitors.
要不是上面情势危急
If it weren't for the crisis topside,
我也不会来找你
you wouldn't be getting one now.
危急
Crisis?
他好有男人味啊
He's so alpha, isn't he?
不过大概不太适合谈恋爱吧
Probably not relationship material, though.
母亲  流哈喇子了
Mother, you're drooling.
请自重
Get ahold of yourself.
你知道黑暗的事吧
You're aware of the Darkness?
哎哟  听上去不妙啊
Yikes. That... that doesn't sound good.
我知道她曾经是什么  但那都是很久以前了
I'm aware of what she was, but that was eons ago.
她被放出来了
She's been released,
所以她正在某个地方
so now she's somewhere...
或者说在地球上的任何一个角落
or everywhere on earth.
怎么发生这种事呢
However did that happen?
重要的是  她对所有的存在都构成了威胁
Point is, she poses a threat to all that exists,
包括你在内
including you.
那我就不得不问第二个问题了
Well, that leads me to my next question.
墨西哥卷饼兄呢
Where's the big burrito himself?
上帝哪去了
Where's God in all of this?
所有迹象表明
All current indications of his presence
他现在不在
are that there are no current indications of his presence.
什么
What?
搭大巴出城玩去啦
Caught the fun bus out of town?
不出所料
Figures.
不过
But...
他最近跟一位相关方取得了联系
Recently he has reached out to an interested party.
谁啊
Who?
我
Me.
你
You?
他回应了我的祈祷
He answered my prayers.
是吗
Did he now?
老爸提出了什么建议
And what was dad's suggestion?
找到你
To seek out you.
少来了
Get outta town.
真的啊
Seriously?
真是没想到啊
Who'd have thunk it?
我在你眼中看到了疲倦
I see the weariness in your eyes,
怀疑
the mistrust.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
是吗
Don't you?
真是难以置信
It's incredible.
这政治宣传能影响这么深远
How it endures, the propaganda.
他深感到我的威胁
He was so threatened by me,
害怕我会实现更完美的造物
fearful that I would make a more perfect creation than he,
于是他放逐了我
so he exiled me.
抹杀了我的存在
Virtually erased me.
通过流传的故事说我是威胁
Passed on stories that I was a threat.
而你哥哥则毫不谦虚
While your brother was going all Kanye,
自吹自擂
blowing his horn?
他鼓励宗教是作为他自负的纪念碑
He encouraged religions as monuments to his ego,
承诺唯唯诺诺者只要崇拜他  就能得到庇护
promised the fearful safety if they'd adore him.
只能听他说了算
His way or the highway.
有些人在这其中找到了安慰
Some people find comfort in that.
黄金法则  哥哥的守护者
Golden rule, brother's keeper.
这是他的世界  他的规则
It is his universe, his rules.
如果没有规则会怎样呢
What if there were no rules?
没有痛苦  没有祈祷
No pain? No prayer?
只有  极乐
Just...bliss.
你跟我在一起时  就会有的那种感觉
That feeling that you have when you're with me.
所有人都会永远享有极乐
For everyone, forever.
你能听到他们在说什么吗
Can you hear what they're saying?
你闭嘴我就能听到了
I could if you'd just shut it.
我完全明白你为什么来找我
I completely get why you came to me.
上帝不容无视  是吧
Can't ignore God, right?
上帝说"跳"  所有人就回"跳多高"
God says, "Jump," everybody says, "How high?"
那么你入伙吗
So does this mean you're on board?
这个嘛
Well...
很多年前  我的确有帮老爸封印了黑暗
I did help dad seal up the Darkness all those years ago.
她真的很难缠
She's quite a force.
即便是当时  就一心想篡夺大权
Determined to take over everything even back then.
脾气特别大
Prone to tantrums.
我能明白老爸为什么要躲起来
I can see why pop is laying low.
话真多啊
A lot of blabber going on.
萨姆总知道不能跟他做交易吧
Surely Sam knows better than to cut some sort of deal.
其实呢  费格斯
You know, Fergus,
有时达成协议  即便是痛苦的协议
sometimes striking a deal, even a painful one,
也许是唯一的选择
may be the only option.
比如你对我下的刺杀令吗
Like the hit you took out on me, for instance?
为人父母不容易啊
It's not easy being a parent,
要清楚何时该拥抱孩子  何时该杀掉他们
knowing when to hug your child, when to kill him.
妹妹一来
Now that sis is here,
上帝就不是唯一的狠角色了
God's not the only circus in town.
她的力量跟上帝一样强大吗
Is she equal to him in power?
纯粹力量吗  当然
Raw power? Sure.
但是她完全没有
But she's got none of the...
经验
experience.
上帝可是个大谋略家
God is a master strategist.
所以你才会来这里
That's why you're here.
怎么说
And why is that?
因为上帝需要我
Well, 'cause God needs me
帮他把猫抓回袋子里
to help put the cat back in the bag.
他自己干不了这事
Can't do it by himself.
这我经历过
Seen that movie.
所以呢
And?
我需要搭"车"出去
And I need a ride out of here.
我在这里面看着还挺好
I mean, I look swell in here and everything,
但到了地面  我会变成黑烟
but I'd be so much smoke topside.
你想要皮囊
You want a vessel.
一具
One who's...
强大到足以容纳我
Strong enough to hold me,
方便
handy,
现在就能用的皮囊
and available now.
理解我的意思吗
Catch my drift?
你具体想要什么
What is it exactly that you want?
你把世界变得"极乐"  "安宁"之后
When you make the world of "bliss" and "peace,"
-你会得到什么  -我应得的
- what's in it for you? - What I deserve.
那是什么
Which is?
一切
Everything.
我是原初  也将会是终结
I was the beginning, and I will be the end.
我会成为唯一
I will be all that there is.
那你就是
So you're...
老大了
you're it.
你就是上帝了
That would make you God.
不
No.
上帝是光明
God was the light.
我是黑暗
I am the dark.
然后呢
Then what?
你现在只需要知道这么多
That's all you need to know for now.
你肯定知道那是没用的
You had to know that was pointless.
我知道你是名战士  抵抗是你的本能
I know that you're a warrior and your instinct is to resist,
可惜
but...
我是不可抗拒的
I can't be resisted.
你真觉得我会同意吗
Did you really expect me to agree to this?
我消失  你占据我的身体
So, what, I just disappear, while you take my body
跑到外面去为所欲为
and get set loose on the world again?
我理解  萨姆  这要求确实有点过
I know. I know, Sam. It's a lot to ask.
可是非常时刻要采取非常举措
But desperate times require desperate measures.
那不是非常  是疯狂
That's not desperate. That's certifiable!
别急  牛仔  深呼吸
Okay, hold on there a second, cowboy. Take a breath.
你还跟克劳力合作呢
You have been working with Crowley.
你早已过了疯狂的边界了
You passed certifiable three off-ramps ago.
我也不喜欢宇宙之主
And look, I'm no fan of the ruler of the universe,
但我还是愿意帮忙
but here I am, ready to pitch in.
萨姆  你以为上帝为什么让你来找我
Sam, why do you think God sent you to me?
是让你来寻求帮助  而我刚说愿意帮了
To get my help, which I only now just offered.
萨姆  你的幻象是上帝之语
Sam, your visions were the word of God.
你不能拒绝的
You can't say no to that.
那是怎么回事
What was that?
未来
The future.
我们相遇的必然结果
The inevitable result of our first meeting.
我们初遇之后你一直有的感觉
What you've been feeling since that moment.
我们都感觉到了
What we both felt,
我们是紧密相连的
that we're bonded.
你是释放了我的人
You're the one who set me free.
不  那只是个意外
No, that was an accident.
那是命运
It was destiny.
你传承了血印
You bore the mark.
我是最初的血印
I am the original mark.
你和我必将在一起
You and I will be together.
不
No.
不  那不可能
No, that's... that's not gonna happen.
这很简单  迪恩
It's so simple, Dean.
我们将成为一体
We will become one.
你为什么不想那样
Why wouldn't you want that?
阿玛拉
Amara.
你要向我们投降  去天堂接受审判
You're going to surrender to us and to the judgment of heaven.
我为什么要屈服于上帝创造的东西
Why ever would I submit to anything of God's creation?
让你们的主人亲自来抓我
Tell your master to come fetch me himself.
天堂全体都高度警戒
All of heaven's on high alert.
如果你反抗  天空中的每个天使
If you resist, each and every angel in the skies
会合力一击毁灭你
will smite you in a single unified blow.
连你都无力抵御
Not even you could survive it.
各位  别激动啊
Fellas, dial it down a bit, okay?
如果你们杀了她
Look, if you take her down,
会有很多人一起陪葬的
a whole bunch of people are gonna die.
现在  牺牲已在所难免
We're at the point where sacrifice is inevitable.
阿玛拉  不
Amara, no!
你做了什么
What have you done?
要来了
It's coming.
他们会毁灭你的
They will smite you.
也许现在他会听到我了
Maybe now he'll hear me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你考虑过了吗  萨姆
So have you thought about it, Sam?
我能期待你的邀请吗
Do I have an invitation to look forward to?
不
No.
我不会这么做的
I won't do it.
一定还有别的办法
There has to be another way.
怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
为什么保护咒失效了
Why did the warding fail?
怎么回事
What's happening?
跟我走  费格斯
Follow me, Fergus.
又在一起了
Together again.
萨姆·温彻斯特  想我了吗
Hey, Sam Winchester, you miss me?
你肯定想了
I bet you did.
我得说  考虑到现在的情况
I have to say, you're... you're extraordinarily calm
你真是格外冷静
given the circumstances.
这和上帝跟我说的情况基本一样
It's pretty much exactly how God told me it was gonna be.
看来我只能照做  碰运气了
Guess I just have to go with it and play my hand.
这本该说得通
And that would make so much sense
如果跟你说话的是上帝的话
if it was God that was doing the talking.
你瞧  萨姆  黑暗降临时
You see, Sam, when the Darkness descended,
对地狱的影响非常大
the impact on hell was massive.
笼子被损坏了
The cage was damaged.
我通过裂缝  探了出去
Through the fissures, I was able to reach out.
进入你头脑的并不是上帝  萨姆
It wasn't God inside your head, Sam.
是我
It was me.
所以你瞧
So you see,
他并不与你同在
he's not with you.
他从未与你同在
He's never been with you.
一直都是我
It was always just...me.
所以我
So I...
我想我的确是你唯一的希望
I guess I am your only hope.
绝不可能
It's never gonna happen.
好吧
Well...
那就住下吧  伙计
Settle in there, buddy.
室友
Hey, roomie...
上铺  下铺
Upper bunk? Lower bunk?
还是想睡一张床
Or do you wanna share?